ROHAN RAWAT

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

9897644759 | rohan.rawat.9897@gmail.com | https://linkedin.com/in/rohannn | https://nnboru.github.io

PROFILE

3+ years of experience working on an agent support platform at Fareportal. Worked on microservice architecture using .NET, SQL Server, MongoDB, React, along with generating daily reports and performing data analysis. Skilled in designing highly complex workflows, handling dependencies and parallelising workload for faster deliveries.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, Fareportal Pvt. Ltd., Gurugram

Jul 2022 — Present

Fareportal is a product-based B2C global travel technology company offering online booking via websites, mobile apps or trained travel agents.

Our team handles post-booking services, such as schedule changes and cancellations for customer bookings. We developed end-to-end flow automation along with its fallback manual agent process, while maintaining reports and reviewing and debugging failure cases.

- Cancellation process broadly includes sending OTP email to customer, charging agent fee, voiding the tickets and ancillaries, cancelling the PNR and processing the refund or airline credit according to fare rules of the associated booking engine/airline.
- For ~450 Flight bookings received per day, we have achieved 94% adoption with 72% automation.
- Onboarded Car Cancellation flow, extended to Hotel, Cross-sell, and Vacation Package cancellation, increasing ~50 bookings/day adoption.

Booking Schedule Change

- This module handles involuntary schedule change from the airline side, where the customer may accept an alternate itinerary offered at the same price or may demand a full refund. For this, customers can use our chatbot integration tool or self-help tool, or connect with an agent.
- For ~70 Flight bookings received per day, we have achieved 96% adoption with 100% automation.

Technologies Used: .NET Web API (C#), React-redux, SQL Server, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ

Internship, APPNIVI IT Solution, Hyderabad

Jul 2019 — Aug 2019

Machine learning with Python □ Data cleansing & abstraction □ graph plotting □ ML algorithms Implementation

EDUCATION

M.Tech (CSE Analytics) - NIT, Delhi - 8.46CGPA B.Tech (CSE) - GBPIET Pauri, Uttarakhand XII - Army Public School, Meerut Cantt

Jul 2020 — Jul 2022 Jul 2016 — Jun 2020 March 2014

PROJECTS

Cattle Biometric Recognition System

MTech Thesis | ML Transfer learning | Python

Worked on a private cattle muzzle dataset and proposed an effective cattle identification method. First, we perform localisation using YOLOv3, then perform top k-class mean image indexing, and finally, SIFT algorithm keypoint matching to identify the input image class. For 395 cattle classes, we achieved an accuracy of 79.8% for identification with near-real-time performance of 4-5 seconds on an i3 processor.

BTech Final year project 2020 | Python Flask | SQLite | JavaScript

A simple chatbot specifically designed for performing math-related tasks like solving equations, drawing graphs, and plotting charts for CSV files.

Stone Paper Scissors @ github &

MERN | Socket.io

The game allows users to create private rooms and share a unique room link for real-time online gameplay across individual devices. There is no limit to the number of players in each room, and users can chat with each other while playing, making for an interactive and engaging experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C#, C++, Python, HTML, CSS, JS

Framework & libraries: NET Web-API/MVC, NodeJS, Express, React, Redux, Bootstrap, Flask, Pygame, Socket.io

Databases: SQL Server, MongoDB, Redis

Tools: Azure, Git, Postman, Kibana, Grafana, Applnsights, RabbitMQ

ACHIEVEMENTS

Competitive programming

- Codechef 5 star www.codechef.com/users/Rohannn
- Codeforces max expert www.codeforces.com/profile/nnboru ICPC Contest 2019-2020 went till the National round

GATE 2020 - score 492

JLPT - N3 level